hey everybody Welcome to The Grow Life
podcast my name is Jeremiah Kowski this
is podcast where I help you grow a
business online make more money
particularly in the coaching and online
course space what I want to talk about
is starting your own online business um
I'm going to go foundational here on
this episode I think you're really going
to like this if you've been thinking
about starting an online business I
think it's going to help you a lot so
one of the things is to like really make
the decision as to why you want to start
an online business do you not like your
job do you want to make more money um
what is that purpose and the truth is is
that to make online business work um you
got to take it seriously you got to make
it something that is something that
you're actually serious about I see a
lot of people they're just dabbling in
online business and they struggle to get
the results that they want and then they
complain because they followed some
framework that they believed was going
to make them a bunch of money and it
didn't now I have Frameworks that I
teach all the time inside of my coaching
program I got free classes right now
where I teach you how to put together
courses and online coaching programs and
how to do that and all the step by steps
of being able to do that I've been in
this industry for over 22 years there's
a process that works there's a system
that works but you can't just look at it
like okay a job where I'm going to do
this I'm going to show up I'm going to
put in the hours and now it's going to
pay me money you got to think much
bigger picture on that and that's why
your business is is solving a problem
for people now the businesses that I
help people with are online courses and
coaching and so we're going to talk
particularly about that business
specifically May you're like I don't
want to start one of those businesses I
want to get into a different business
model okay great you can research that
you can learn that you can learn new
skills and one of the biggest reasons
why a lot of people tell me that they
don't have their own online business
because they don't have the skills that
it takes nobody taught them the skills
of what it takes to be able to do the
types of things that they want to do you
can learn the skills today we have so
many different tools out there from
perplexity which is an AI tool to chat
GPT to YouTube to be able toar learn
skills you can join coaching programs
you can listen to podcasts like this one
from any number of Industries and learn
things that you never had access to
before okay it's going to take you time
it's not going to happen overnight but
understand that if you trust the process
and you actually are serious about it
because that's one of the most important
things you got to actually be serious
about it I mean a lot of people they
like I want to start my own online
business but they're not serious about
it they're not intentional they don't
actually want to do so they they they
think they do they have this dream of
doing so but at the end of the day
they're not really in a place where they
can do that and so what separates those
that are actually successful from those
that struggle is
that they go to a place where they take
it
seriously mentally physically they
structure their life and they organize
their life around the success and the
results that they want and so for you
for you to be able to get the kind of
results that you want in your own
business for you to be able to
accomplish the things that you want it
starts with taking it seriously not just
dabbling not just oh maybe I want to
make a little bit of money online it's
like okay I'm going to make this a huge
part of what I do your front-facing
identity on social media every
interaction that you have with people
outside of like close friends and family
is going to be promoting business okay
so understand and you might be like wait
a sec I don't want to be that guy I
don't want to be that person that's all
about talking about my business can I
tell you
this I'm not that way with my close
friends and family but to anybody else
that I
meet the only front-facing thing that
they're going to get from me is my
business and what I do in business and
the things that I accomplish in
business and through
that I'm very successful and and when I
didn't when I was passive with it when I
was just you know dabbling cuz I I had a
period where I was just dabbling where I
wasn't as serious about what I'm doing
right now um I struggled to be able to
get those kind of results I've been in
this industry for over 22 years but I
did not make everything that I put out
there my reputation how I presented
myself how I showed up in different
parts of life to be about business until
the past couple of years and so that's
one of the things that you have to do is
that you got to make a decision that we
are now stepping into the identity of
business owner now here's the other
thing the first business that you launch
might not make you a ton of money you
might not produce the results that you
want it might not make you the kind of
money that you want so you got to have
tenacity you got to have the ability to
fail be okay with failure you got to
accept failure you got to accept that
things aren't always going to work out
and listen this is not that's not going
to sell a bunch of courses by me saying
this I am hurting my business by me
telling you that I would make far more
money if I was dishonest and actually
said oh it's so easy and everybody makes
a bunch of
money I'm not going to be dishonest with
you I'm going to be truthful in
everything that I tell you it's hard
there's hard stuff you got to do and
you're not always going to produce the
results that you want but if you stick
with it if you plug into a proven system
like what we have in my client growth
accelerator program like what we have in
my coaching programs you can get results
you can get the results that you want
and so if you want to get those kind of
results in your business if you want to
create those kind of results it takes a
decision that I'm going to go after this
and make
this important to me I'm going to make
this a big part of what I do I'm going
to do it as important as if I was
getting a job as important as when I
decide to make make a lifestyle change
to get married as important as when I
make a decision that I'm going to um
focus on my health and fitness if I make
a decision that I'm going to move to a
new city get new friends change that
because what it is is business is a
lifestyle change it is a change that you
are making to how you live your life and
what ends up happening is from the
outside of that on the other end of that
is a life that's different than you ever
ever imagined I see a lot of people
where they're wanting to build a
business and they're not willing to make
changes to their life they want the same
life of what they've always always had
and then wondering well why am I not
making the kind of money that I want to
make and then they look at people like
myself who have literally had to
transform our lives from the ground up
to be able to make business happen and
we think that for some reason we don't
have to be that way I don't have to be
that way I'm special enough or it's just
not going to be that way for me I'm just
going to keep doing what I've been doing
and then that's going to make me
successful I don't mean to be harsh here
some of you might be taking this like
wow Jeremiah's really rude really mean
really harsh no I don't mean that way
I'm saying this as
like hopeful
because as soon as that trigger that
switch flips inside of you where you're
like I am going to make a decision to
change my life to change my family's
future to do something differently than
I've ever done before I'm going to
operate differently I'm going to show up
differently there are people who know me
now that are going to see a different
version of myself showing up and being
willing to let go of that version of you
that always showed up to let the new
version of you show up that you need to
be able to accomplish everything that's
inside of you and so for you to do this
it takes a choice it takes a decision
that I'm no longer going to continue
living my life the way that I've always
lived it and I'm going to be living a
brand new life a brand new
existence in this okay and so then what
you do is we start creating a product we
start creating some kind of an offer
something that we can sell to people a
digital product a digital course a
coaching program you know in my client
growth accelerator we walk you through
how to do that I actually have a a class
right now on my website it's uh October
25th right now on my website called
starting your coaching or online course
business from scratch right here brand
new class how to make $10 to $225,000
per month with your own business and I
walk you through stepbystep the whole
process of how to start one of these
businesses the right way what are all
the things that you need to do what are
the things that you need to know what
are the platforms to use all that I
break that down for you in that that's
not what this episode is from there I
want to just give you a birds I view in
this episode of getting to that place
where you're making a decision to
actually start one of those business and
I think you absolutely need to you
absolutely need to start a business once
you have a product created now it comes
time to Market it it comes time to
promote it it comes time to find the
people that are going to become your
clients and this is one of the biggest
things that people avoid because they
are afraid of their reputation they're
afraid of how they're going to look to
everybody what everybody's going to
think about them and and they think that
maintaining that is actually the success
strategy that's going to produce the
results your reputation matters about
your integrity your reputation matters
about your your
character but if you're concerned about
how do I look to other people so I'm not
going to promote my business because I'm
afraid they're going to think that oh
I'm I'm just all about that business
thing like that's that's a way of
thinking that we need to change we need
to shift and we need to realize that you
got to promote your business if you want
to be successful and you have to learn
how to sell and you have to learn how to
get people to buy from you you have to
learn how to get people who have no idea
who you are to become a client of yours
you got to learn how to become a
communicator you got to learn how to
communicate on video and then be able to
sell through video recorded video
whether it be not like in a format of
you necessarily need a podcast you don't
need a podcast you don't need a YouTube
channel but you need to record video
content that connects with people at
scale the way that we build Business
Online online today is you record
videos and you send those videos to
people that are looking for the thing
that you help them with and then through
that they make a decision to become a
client of yours and to work with you and
so then by doing that you're able to
connect with the right people bring them
into your
ecosystem and close more sales and get
more clients and get people to start to
work with you through that okay
and so there's a process and there's
skills that you need to learn in that
and that's exactly what I Mentor people
on in my accelerator program one of the
biggest skills is learning your
communication skills you know I
struggled with communication for years I
did not know how to communicate how to
talk on camera how to feel confident on
camera and today you're looking at
somebody who I think I have a great
camera presence I think I show up well
um but I didn't have that skill before
and I learned it by getting out of my
own head and this is one of the biggest
tips that I want to share with you today
is I want to help you realize that the
biggest thing that stops us from being
able to be successful in promoting our
business is we are way too concerned
about how we look to other people we are
way too concerned about sounding right
saying the right things structuring it
in a way that's going to make everybody
do the thing that we want and make them
want to buy from us and and and doing it
and saying it all perfectly when really
if we can learn to just show up as
ourselves be yourself the way that you
would with your friends with your your
family without overthinking it get out
of your own head get out of your own way
you can be far more successful
with 10% of the same
effort by doing that and I'll tell you
in my life anytime I've looked at where
I've been the most successful
financially it's when I got out of my
own way I got out of my head I got I
stopped trying to do it all perfect I
stopped trying to say it all perfect
I stopped trying to structure it all in
a way that was going to produce the
greatest
results and and I'm one of those people
that does that like crazy I spent a lot
of my effort trying to make everything
just so to make it work and I'll tell
you every time that I've done that I
have failed and not made the kind of
money that I want my business has
suffered and my family life has suffered
and my connections with people have
suffered and as soon as I let go of that
whenever I do I let go of the
perfectionism I let go of that need to
be perfect I just show up and I just
have fun with it I just talk just
communicate I just be myself makes me a
lot more money said Jeremiah that's easy
for
you I'm not that way it's not my
personality it wasn't my personality
either you might say Jeremiah it's easy
for you cuz you're a guy I'm not a
male I've had a lot of women tell me
that can I tell you this women actually
succeed far more more in this business
model than men do um and especially when
they can learn how to be authentic off
the cuff not trying to tailor themselves
perfectly in a way that sounds or looks
a certain way I know culture tells you
you got to be that way I know Society
tells you you got to be that way but if
you want to be successful in a business
online you got to shift that you got to
change that and you got to literally
show up without
overthinking and learn how to talk and
communicate with people and then Market
yourself with confidence not be afraid
of what everybody thinks about you let
go of that worry let go of that fear let
go of that insecurity and just show up
and just be
yourself and then when you can put that
together into a course you figure out
what's a topic I can help people with
you start talking about it you start
having fun with it you start just
talking like you would like you're
talking to a friend helping them through
a problem and then you're able to sell
that you're able to actually put price
tag of $1,000 $2,000 $55,000 on a
product that you can sell
online and then you find 500 people that
want that product that's how you make a
million bucks you find a 100 people that
want that product that's how you make
$100,000 and it's not hard to find 10
people a month that want to work with
you on that when you learn how to be
consistent with these skills and again
that's exactly in my client growth
accelerator we work with you through
knowing what are the best topics to do
this with how do you dial in your
messaging how do you dial in your
promotion process how do you sell like a
master without being sleazy or slimy so
that you can have consistent income
massive impact so that you have
everything dialed in with absolute
Clarity on what to do and that's what
creates Financial Freedom and time
freedom in your life so that you don't
have to be working hundreds of hours to
do this see that's the thing a lot of
people think this takes hundreds of
hours to do
this I don't have hundreds of hours in
my day I got I got two
kids I I just I don't I I don't have
that much time to work in a week and so
the way that I make it work on less than
5 to 10 hours a week is get out of my
own way get out of my head stop
overthinking stop taking 10 hours to
process through one thing that I'm going
to do and just press record just be off
the tough just learn how to do that and
challenge myself to do the uncomfortable
things when they are
uncomfortable and it produces massive
results so listen again I'd love to work
with you in my accelerator program
through this I'd love for you to check
out some of the free classes that we
have over my website and I'd love to
help you build one of these businesses
to be successful grow your life
everybody we'll talk soon stay plugged
in the podcast have a good one
[Music]